Ladies and gentlemen, you've heard all the evidence.
I submit that this was not a hot -blooded crime of passion.
Consider this, a revolver holds six bullets, not eight.
That means that he fired the gun empty and then stopped to
reload.
By the power vested in me by the state of Maine,
I hereby order you to serve two life sentences back to back.
One for each of your victims.
So be it.
Send you here for life, that's exactly what they take.
I believe in two things, discipline and the Bible.
Here you'll receive both.
Andy came to Shawshank prison in 1947.
Why'd you do it?
I didn't since you asked.
You can fit right in.
I must admit, I didn't think much of Andy first time I
laid eyes on him.
He had a quiet way about it, a walk, a talk that
just wasn't normal around here.
There are places in the world that aren't made out of stone.
There's something inside that they can't touch.
What are you talking about?
Hope.
Let me tell you something, my friend.
Hope is a dangerous thing.
Damn it, new friend, you're putting me behind.
You drive a man insane.
You better be sick or dead in there, I kid you not.
I better get used to that idea.
Oh my holy God.
As it comes down to a simple choice, you're gonna like busy
living or die.
Busy living or get busy dying.
Damn right.